♪From primal chaos to the starry sky♪
♪In the whole world,
we shall hold the balance♪
♪The cauldron tempers divine blades♪
♪The furnace refines the empty void♪
♪The Way is in mystic fate♪
♪Be brave enough to split
the primal chaos wide open♪
[Pull Strings]
[Adapted from the novel
by Yan Gui Zheng Zhuan]
[Marriage Division, Celestial Court]
♪Birds in the trees fly in pairs♪
Liu Yan'er, Wang Qi.
[Liu Yan'er Wang Qi]
I'll bind you two tighter.
May you grow old together.
♪Green hills and waters smile♪
Another pair made.
Fate sees all. Fate sees all!
[Grand Mage of Voidcity]
Grand Mage.
[Supreme Elder's first disciple,
Three Sects of the Way]
Old man,
I just had a dream.
I dreamed that by Mentor's order,
I came here to boost human procreation.
The results are quite pleasing.
Grand Mage, this is no dream.
Perhaps you are actually here for this,
but you fell asleep after arriving
at Ascendance Sect, East Land.
Then I'll take a short rest and return.
Grand Mage, Grand Mage.
You've already taken three naps.
Please, do some proper work.
If this delays
the Human Sect's marriages,
Eastwood Duke won't let me off.
Eastwood Duke?
Eastwood Duke is no trouble.
Grand Mage, Grand Mage.
Please, please.
Please, look.
This is
the Book of Marriages
of Ascendance Sect.
Please, take a look.
On this
are recorded all birth dates
and names
of the couples.
I never imagined
that over these centuries,
our Ascendance Sect
would have so many couples.
No, no.
This right here
is just from the past three months.
This
is from the past several centuries.
[Book of Marriages of Ascendance Sect]
That's it?
Were you dozing off?
I wouldn't dare.
It's empty inside.
Over the past centuries,
your Ascendance Sect hasn't had
a single match.
But in just the past three months,
480 couples have formed.
480 couples...
Ones, tens, hundreds, thousands.
Four hundred and eighty.
Grand Mage, you're so clever!
From what I've observed,
all these love matches
come from a single new sprout.
This sprout has sparked many matches,
yet it itself remains untouched.
He's got three admirers.
Admirers?
But he rejected all of them.
This is not an easy thing.
The admirers are trying.
Look.
I think this virtuous talent
must be calm and self-restraint.
That's why
he turned down three fine matches.
How amusing!
Why not invite the Moon Elder
to bring them together?
Grand Mage,
actually, I am the Moon Elder.
You are the Moon Elder?
So, you're the Moon Elder!
Nice to meet you.
How nice indeed.
If you're the Moon Elder,
why don't you just tie them together?
That won't do, that won't do.
The Marriage Division can only assist
the marriage destinies
of all living beings.
It must not be forced.
I never imagined
that in our Way lineage,
there is such a fascinating person.
What is this person's name?
Li Changshou,
Jade Division,
Ascendance Sect.
[Li Changshou]
[Episode 5]
You still can't channel your power?
Every time I try to channel it,
I recall Yuan Qing's words that day.
What did Yuan Qing say?
He said
that I don't know what this sword means,
nor why I wield it.
This question has been troubling me,
keeping me from using this new sword
to release my power.
It's alright.
Maybe
this sword just isn't right for you.
You have the Firescale Sword, right?
The edge and tip are broken.
I buried it.
You buried it?
Let it be buried then.
You'll surely find a better one.
If the heart is there,
the sword is there.
Please take your leave.
Heart...
Senior,
isn't that a bit too dismissive?
She's venomous.
She's worse than the Gnatsting Needle.
We have to steer clear.
I understand.
You even understand that?
Your sword isn't tangible.
It's a Qi refiner's inner righteousness.
The sword-bearer relies
not on the blade,
but on a righteous spirit.
Your lesson is spot on.
I'm truly convinced.
This is my junior. Ask her.
I'll leave her to you.
[Hall of United Spirits]
Senior, he...
Senior...
He's just like that.
He'll chat and then suddenly scowl.
Once you've spent more time with him,
you'll surely dislike it.
Kindred souls value a knowing heart.
So carefree and noble.
Truly a lofty vision, a broad mind.
Senior Youqin,
you know so many idioms!
Just a little.
Junior,
may I come visit often?
Often?
Look at me.
Every day, I have to sweep, mop,
[Hall of United Spirits]
and wipe tables.
I lit all those candles, you know.
I'm so tired my back is killing me.
You gotta pay me for all this work.
Fifty a day.
One hundred.
I don't have change.
How about I pay for fifty years upfront?
Forget spirit stones; it's no big deal.
It's all the same.
But our division
hasn't had an outsider in years.
Jiu...
Aunt Jiu Jiu.
Is Changshou here?
Does he have a project or something
that needs my help?
He...
He went out.
Senior sure loves giving orders.
Aunt Jiu Jiu lives for her wine.
With wine, she'll gladly help.
Did she pay spirit stones too?
She...
Isn't she here to help?
She's paying with labor.
Right.
Aunt, over there.
A bit to your left. There.
[South Qian]
Three pieces.
Right.
Three more pieces on the right.
And in front of you.
[Five, Heaven, Ten, Earth]
Three pieces there.
Line them up a little more.
All right, all right.
Li Changshou!
Keep going.
Yes.
I'm worn out.
You're amazing.
Three ten-thousandths done.
What did you say?
Li Changshou,
you call this a small task?
28 binding arrays.
76 hidden nodes.
Purplegold Array Plate,
Perpetual Motion Millstone.
Even the sect's grand array
isn't this complete.
What are you really planning?
How could it rival the grand array?
I merely seek some convenience.
For the Sky-Scraping Vine,
I crossed a powerful figure.
I have to be prepared.
Why bring this trouble to me
when I abstain from wine??
Heavens.
Are you trying to end me?
I know quitting wine is hard.
Nonsense.
This is worse
than getting struck by lightning.
I can't touch it.
I've quit drinking.
Uncle, this isn't alcohol.
This is my exclusive original creation:
Captivating Brew.
The perfect substitute.
Satisfaction guaranteed.
I still can't touch it.
Changshou,
from today on,
we'll each use our own titles.
You call me Aunt,
and I'll call you Brother.
Brother? Let's skip that.
But lately,
I've been busy with preparations.
I'm anxious to advance my cultivation.
As for these physical tasks...
I'll take care of them.
Leave it all to me.
Rest assured.
Grand Mage,
with all this sweet talk,
how could he resist?
It seems
that to enlighten that stubborn stone,
we must rely on the Tree of Yearning.
But
for a trivial mortal romance,
this office has no precedent
to use such a sacred object.
Grand Mage,
what do you think?
I think
precedents are meant to be broken.
Look at the three...
Three stars.
Three admirers.
Yeah, three pillars.
It was heaven's will, after all.
We must not waste it.
Moreover,
this is for the Human Clan's prosperity.
It's understandable.
Grand Mage,
with your words,
I will dare to act on it.
Go!
[Hall of United Spirits]
An illusion.
Such a real illusion.
Could it be Fairy Yunxiao?
Just for a piece of Sky-Scraping Vine,
she wants to break my cultivation?
How can she do that?
Here goes the Everlasting Bond.
[Lan Ling'e]
Senior.
What kind of twisted thought is this?
Illusion, disperse!
Break!
Everlasting Bond!
[Youqin Xuanya]
Senior.
Senior Changshou,
if I had a boat ticket,
would you come with me?
Not a chance.
Break!
♪I grasp the vast firmament♪
♪Karma never falls empty♪
I...
Everlasting Bond!
[Jiu Jiu]
Changshou.
Do you want to go for a ride?
Break!
You brat.
I don't believe it.
Alright, that's enough.
Stop embarrassing yourself
before the Grand Mage.
Eastwood Duke.
You...
Grand Mage.
Look at yourself.
I was just about to praise you.
The Marriage Division's results
have soared lately.
I thought you'd finally improved.
I never thought
you couldn't even handle
such a small matter.
Eastwood Duke, what brings you here?
How could I not come?
Put some effort in.
Don't let the Grand Mage of Voidcity
make a mockery of our Celestial Court.
Put some effort in?
But he...
Back off.
This... he...
Grand Mage.
You be careful too.
You...
Three steps back.
As expected of the immortals.
They saw through my fear of karma,
hitting me where it hurts.
Hey.
No gifts this holiday.
Let's just spend some time together.
Just open your eyes and look at me.
I don't believe
you have no feelings for me.
See you tomorrow.
See you every day.
Immortals, your move is formidable.
Bet I still have my trump card.
[Lifespan Filter:
Portrait of Old Beauties]
Flowers fade; all must age.
Greed, anger, folly, love,
do not bother me.
Break!
Eastwood Duke.
Eastwood Duke, are you alright?
Are you alright, Eastwood Duke?
His aspiration for the Way
is simply indestructible.
A rarity for all ages.
How admirable.
How terrifying.
This clever one, start already.
It's already over.
Moon Elder,
he's actually more formidable than you.
Grand Mage, you're insulting me!
Well, in that case,
let me try.
Look!
He bested the Demon Emperor
and saved the Six Clans.
Though often carefree,
when the moment counts,
his noble bearing appears,
with mighty power.
I...
What's wrong with my arm?
My arm...
Senior.
Are you all right?
I'm fine.
Are you truly fine?
I really am.
- Truly?
- Senior.
- I'm fine.
- Let me look.
- What of your arm?
- I'm fine.
Senior.
I'm fine.
Let me see.
- I'm fine.
- Senior.
- Your arm?
You look far from fine.
I'm truly fine.
- Are you sure?
- I am.
Something's wrong with your arm.
My arm is fine.
- Another illusion!
- You're hurt!
- Break!
- Senior, you're hurt!
Senior.
Are you all right?
Break! Break!
If I can't break it, then...
Run!
What is he trying to break?
His words are so deep.
Yes, a bit mystical.
So mystical.
Sorry, sorry.
After all,
we were too hasty,
causing that mortal to lose his arm.
No, this won't do.
We must take
our responsibility.
We must apologize to him.
Moon Elder.
Understood.
Stellar Dreamweaver.
Our dream-sending treasure.
He's a mortal,
so he will sleep and rest.
Once this mortal falls asleep,
we'll use the power of the Dreamweaver
to lead him here in his dream.
Then, you can properly apologize to him.
I apologize?
What's wrong?
Then... you?
He?
I apologize?
Of course.
It must be you.
Be sincere.
Got it.
That power is terrifying.
Once in a dream, I'll be defenseless.
I wonder which great deity it is,
trying to ruin my cultivation.
But I've planned for years.
I can't let it all fall apart here.
At worst,
I just won't sleep.
[Half a month later]
Eastwood Duke,
it's been half a month already.
This thing's been dead silent.
Is it broken or something?
What do you know?
You'd fall apart before it does.
As long as this mortal is tired, weak,
dazed, and distracted,
with his mind wavering,
this Stellar Dreamweaver
can drag him into a dream instantly.
But then again,
this mortal is really annoying.
It's already been half a month.
How come he hasn't slackened at all?
Doesn't he get tired living like this?
It's been half a month already.
If we keep putting off this apology,
his arm will be fully healed.
It seems he's not destined
to get an apology.
Not destined? We'll make it destined.
It's the Grand Mage's blunder.
We must handle the aftermath properly.
Otherwise, it'll be our failure.
Whether his arm heals or not,
we must take responsibility.
Alright, I'm tired too.
I need to go back and sleep.
No, I need to go
sort out official duties.
Keep a close watch.
Watch until he loosens up.
Goodbye, Eastwood Duke.
I'll keep watch.
This place is called Tiger's Mouth.
If you're too sleepy to bear it,
just pinch yourself a couple of times.
Pinch hard.
Ow! Ow!
Don't worry. I'll keep a good watch.
Rest assured.
I'm wide awake.
[Hall of United Spirits]
I'm a cultivator.
With my Qi going on,
staying awake for years is nothing.
Chattering in the dead of night!
You cultivate, but others need sleep!
Cultivate!
Cultivate some decency!
Have you no decency?
You think I have no temper?
Where is this?
Just now...
I've persevered for so long.
How can I quit halfway?
All sensual obstructions, break!
Young man.
Hold on!
Young man, hold on!
What the...?
Young man.
You... you...
I've been waiting for you.
Come, come, young man.
What are you doing?
Young man.
Just look over here.
Look here.
Where is this?
Red threads have no end,
yet flowers have masters.
Love never ages;
the moon is forever round.
Could this be...
Exactly.
Under a full moon,
beneath the Tree of Yearning,
this is the Union Palace.
I am the Moon Elder.
Heaven decrees:
I rule Three Realms' marriages.
Young man,
I've long admired you from afar.
Is my intro that moving?
I love this sky so deeply.
There, there, good kid. Don't cry.
There, there.
Don't cry.
That's what happened.
You're so selfless and magnanimous.
[Li Changshou]
That's truly rare.
It's fine.
When others waste their time
on idle thoughts,
I put my time into cultivation.
Since we know
your determination in cultivation,
we won't press you.
As for the Grand Mage of Voidcity,
he won't mind
such trifles.
This involves the Grand Mage too?
More than just involved.
It's like tangled lotus roots.
He's the real breaker
of your...
I didn't hear that. Understood.
Well, the Celestial Court
is newly founded.
The Grand Mage of Voidcity
is a high immortal.
It's only proper for him
to tend to daily affairs.
Of course, of course.
I'll be honest with you.
Since childhood,
I've longed for the Celestial Court.
Now, to actually be here
is truly a dream come true.
I never imagined
that our humble Celestial Court
would have such a devoted admirer.
Why not stay for a drink?
I can tell you something
about the Celestial Court.
Well...
A little drink.
Just a little drink.
Then,
let's have a little drink.
Let me tell you, Changshou.
I'm having such a hard time.
I've been on duty here
for thousands of years.
I haven't had a single day off.
And they'd even have you
work 24 hours a day.
Not even a stick of incense's rest.
The quota for the Book
of Marriages is so high.
How can a little old man like me
finish it all?
And if you can't finish,
you'll be punished.
He never stops to think
how absurd those quotas are, right?
Also,
nowadays,
why do you mortals stop falling in love?
Well, work and life pressure is huge.
There's just no time.
No time?
If you don't fall in love,
I just can't meet my matchmaking quota.
If I can't meet my quota,
Eastwood Duke will really scold me.
Why don't you
just fall in love, huh?
Alright, I understand.
I get you.
Here.
However,
speaking of which, Changshou,
I've been in the Celestial Court
for ages.
This is the first time
someone's had a drink
and chatted with me.
Moon Elder,
as long as you want,
I'll come to your dreams after I sleep
to drink with you.
Don't just come in your dreams.
Take a post at the Celestial Court.
Come work with me.
How fine to drink with me face-to-face.
Moon Elder,
there you go joking again.
The Celestial Court is so lofty.
I'm just a junior.
I dare not dream of it.
Lofty, my foot.
Be it heaven or earth, work is work.
Right?
Let me tell you.
Some affairs
are beyond the control
of the Celestial Court.
Why?
It lacks hands.
There's too much to oversee.
So, it simply can't manage.
Well,
may I ask
one thing?
What does the Celestial Court
want to control?
It wants to control a lot of things.
For example, Eastwood Duke
has recently been worried
about one person.
Tell me about it.
Go on.
She's called
Fairy Yunxiao.
Fairy Yunxiao?
You know her?
No.
How could I possibly know an immortal?
Exactly.
Fairy Yunxiao is so high above.
How could a Human Clan disciple
know her?
Yes.
Then, tell me.
What is Fairy Yunxiao's background?
Let me tell you
about Fairy Yunxiao's
background.
Fairy Yunxiao
is the first cloud given form.
She was born a Quasi-Saint.
Then she joined the Seizing Sect
under Heavenreach Master,
known as the mightiest war goddess.
At first,
Fairy Yunxiao never fought for anything.
But for some reason,
she's become a different person.
She roams around plundering
magic instruments.
A lovely young girl,
now a wicked fiend.
Yunxiao!
Senior,
is Yunxiao back?
She was just here.
All these years, not a word.
[Zhao Gongming, Seizing Sect]
Where did she go?
She could at least have told us.
I see.
No wonder she's so formidable.
At first, the Celestial Court wanted
to curb her actions.
But Fairy Yunxiao
is elusive.
We can't find her.
Besides, she's too powerful.
She can't be tamed.
So, the Celestial Court let it be.
But something's happened recently.
The Celestial Court had to act.
Recently,
Fairy Yunxiao
has been searching
for the Sea-Calming Pillar.
The Sea-Calming Pillar?
Isn't that the Golden Cudgel?
What cudgel?
Who's great?
You're great.
You misheard.
You might not know
about the Sea-Calming Pillar.
It was here before Pangu
created the world.
Even now, no one knows
where the Sea-Calming Pillar
actually is.
In all the Three Realms,
fewer than ten know.
Shouldn't it be in the East Sea?
You know?
I guessed.
Don't you know?
You...
How would I know?
Do I look like someone
ranked in the top ten
of the Three Realms?
Why wouldn't you?
To me, you seem
more like the top three.
You sweet-talker.
Moon Elder.
Well.
Let me boldly ask
another question.
If I
help the Celestial Court
settle this Fairy Yunxiao matter,
would the Celestial Court then
notice me?
You're drunk.
Just kidding.
Starting to brag, huh?
If you can handle Fairy Yunxiao,
forget about working for me.
You'll just become a high immortal.
You'll be my boss.
My boss...
My boss.
Thirty years of effort finally paid off.
The road ahead is bright.
Now, I just need to head
to the East Sea,
find the Sea-Calming Pillar,
and guard it.
Then, I'll rise to the top.
What's this?
The Tribulation Cloud?
Could it be
Mentor's Tribulation Cloud?
Why are there such dark clouds
gathering above our sect?
Who's facing the Tribulation?
Could it be
someone's facing the Tribulation?
Here, Mentor.
You need all this.
Here.
Put them all here.
Senior,
why not let Mentor face it
in Jade Division?
The Griefbane Division is
the sect's main division.
Outside, the Protective Array
will activate.
Maybe it can reduce
the lightning's impact.
Alright, alright.
Here, Mentor.
Here.
Here, Mentor, take this.
Take this Settlebreath Pill.
And the Jadevoid Powder,
Dragon-Tiger Potion.
Primordial Pill.
Open up.
This is a Lightning Rod.
According to research,
Thunderfall Wood can weaken
the Tribulation by 36%.
Take the Settlebreath Pill now.
Right.
Hurry, open wide, Mentor.
Chew, chew. Yes, yes.
What are you doing to me?
Helping you survive the Tribulation!
Despite all our planning,
your Tribulation Clouds came so soon.
Good thing we were well-prepared.
Mentor, don't worry.
These items on you
will shield you
from five lightning strikes.
- Yes, and this.
- I got a birdcage too.
At worst...
Are you the mentor, or am I?
Mentor...
I know you're worried about me.
I understand your intentions.
But the Tribulation is a pivotal trial.
I must endure it with my body
to bear each bolt of thunder.
Only then can I gain Fate's recognition.
Only then can I say
that I am a true cultivator.
But Mentor...
I know.
I know you are afraid.
I'm afraid too.
When thunder strikes,
my end will be decided.
I'm not afraid of failing the trial.
I'm afraid of...
I'm afraid that if I never return,
how you two rascals
will carry on alone.
Mentor.
Whether I live or die,
it is all the heavenly mandate.
We must face the heavenly mandate,
instead of resorting to heterodox ways.
This is a cultivator's righteous heart.
This is also
my final lesson for you.
Changshou.
I'm here.
Take good care of your junior.
Don't let her suffer again.
I'll be back soon.
If I don't return,
on festive days,
light a stick of incense for me.
When the incense burns out
and smoke curls,
it's me coming to see you.
Mentor,
I obey.
Kids, look.
I never thought
my Tribulation Cloud
would be magnificent.
♪I know the world's full of deceit♪
Mentor.
♪Put on a good show♪
♪Why not change forms and play♪
♪I wish to view the world as art♪
♪But the years are full of chaos♪
♪Caught in karma, stained by dust♪
Whether I'm alive or dead,
whether I make it or not,
today,
I'll accept it all calmly.
♪Let them all come♪
♪There's a perfect plan for everything♪
♪Who's clamoring behind♪
♪Acting like fierce demons♪
Strike!
Come on!
Well.
I'm the Turtle Minister of the East Sea,
here to convey the Dragon King's decree.
I'm here to...
Well...
This is the Human Clan's etiquette?
Understood.
The snow stopped.
You don't understand.
It's been so long since we last met.
The Human Clan is so polite.
It warms my heart.
This is the Ascendance Sect?
What are
all these things?
Your Highness,
they're humans.
So this is
human.
Welcome, Prince Ao Jia
of the East Sea.
♪See mortal joys and sorrows♪
♪Reunions and partings, as fate unfolds♪
♪Alas, love has many twists and turns♪
♪Memories filled with sorrow♪
♪Slowly, wishes turn to regret♪
♪You've gone afar, like mist fading♪
♪Tearfully,
this life's bond is not over♪
♪Past fragments vanish into night♪
♪Down a few more cups of wine♪
♪Through land and sea,
I ask you to come♪
♪For honor's sake, upright and grand♪
♪Alas, our story is short♪
♪Slowly, wishes turn to regret♪
♪You've gone afar, like mist fading♪
♪Tears fall, this fate's not done♪
♪Past fragments vanish into night♪